<section id="workingwithodenadmin_history">
	<title>History</title>

	<para>
		View for checking work results along with deployment lists.
	</para>

	<section id="workingwithodenadmin_history_main">
		<title>Searching Histories</title>
		
		<para>
			You can read the deployment records. 
			All deployments have a unique ID. This ID can be check in the first column. 
			In column order it shows the deployment ID and whether the deployment was a success (green for success, red for failure), 
			the name of Job that executes the deployment, the time of deployment, 
			the number of deployed files (the number of files that succeeded/the total number of files to be deployed), 
			and the Id of User that executed the deployment. 
		</para>
		
		<para>
			When you click deployment Id, you can check the details of deployment. 
			You can check which files were deployed, and which files were not deployed.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			You can check the deployments that fit specific conditions. 
			When you enter the name of deployed file in File, 
			you can see the list of all deployments of the file. 
			Other than File, this list can also be seen through User Id and Job. 
			If Failed Only is checked, you will see the list of only failed deployments. 
			Therefore, if you want the see the entire list of deployments, uncheck Failed Only.
		</para>

		<note>
			<para>
				Deployment records are saved for 365 days as default. 
				This can be changed through log.duration property of core/conf/oden.ini. Shown in days.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>

	<section id="workingwithodenadmin_history_detail">
		<title>Searching Deploy File List</title>

		<para>
			You can check the details of specific deployments. 
			From the left column you can see whether the file deployment was a success (green for success, red for failure), 
			the name of Target Server, the name of deployed file, the deployment mode 
			(Add for deploying a file that did not previously exist, Update for replacing a previous file with a new file, 
			Delete for deleting Target Server file), and the Error Message that shows when deployment fails.
		</para>
		<para>
			Can be searched with deployment file name, and can be filtered by deployment mode. 
			If Failed Only is checked, you can search only items that failed deployment.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>