<section id="workingwithodenadmin_user">
	<title>User</title>

	<para>
		View that registers and gives authority to user that can carry out deployment, 
		controls authority, and can delete registered user. 
		Because it controls user information, only authorized users can access this view.
	</para>

	<note>
			<para>
				This function can only be used by Admin role account.
			</para>
		</note>
	<section id="workingwithodenadmin_user_main">
		<title>User List</title>
		
		<para>
			The User list only shows registered users. 
			Authority given to user which the Role is Deployer is provided for each Job. 
			Detail and History information of only Authorized Job can be checked. 
		</para>
		
		<para>
			User which the Role is Admin has authority on all Jobs, so it says <emphasis role="bold">All Jobs</emphasis> on the Assigned Job List. 
			However, even for user that has authority on all Jobs, 
			all Job Lists show in Assigned Job List when Role is Deployer.
			
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="workingwithodenadmin_user_add">
		<title>Add User</title>
		
		<para>
			User can be added by using the Add button on the top of the page. 
			On the bottom of the page, you will see a place to enter user information, 
			If you click a registered user, you can see information on the user. 
			When you wish to add a new user while checking user information, 
			initialize the user detail information that is shown when clicking the Add button, and enter relevant information.
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">User ID</emphasis> : ID to be used by user 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Role Name</emphasis> : Authority of user to be registered (Admin / Deployer) 
					</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Admin : Can access all Jobs, can access User menu</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Deployer : Can be accessed only for assigned Jobs, cannot access User menu</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Password / Confirm Password</emphasis> : Password to be used by user 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Assign Job</emphasis> : Job List which the user has access to 
						(Separated with comma(,) when there are two or more Jobs)
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>			
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="workingwithodenadmin_user_remove">
		<title>Remove User</title>
		
		<para>
			You can delete a user account from the User list by clicking the User's recycle bin icon.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				All accounts except the user account (oden) basically provided for account management can be deleted.
			</para>		
		</note>
	</section>

</section>