<section id="install_installinganyframeoden">
	<title>Installing The Oden</title>

	<section id="install_installinganyframeoden_serverandAgents">
		<title>Server and Agents</title>

		<para>
			In Oden, there is Server mode and Agent mode. 
			<footnote>
				<para>
					In this document, the server in which file will be deployed is called Target Server.
				</para>
			</footnote>
			Agent is installed in Target Server in which file will be deployed, 
			and deploys files according to the commands of Oden Server. 
			Oden Server manages several Agents, 
			and user gives commands to Oden Server through GUI environment such as command line and Oden Admin. 
			User cannot directly give commands to Agent, but only through Oden Server.
		</para>

		<section
			id="install_installinganyframeoden_serverandAgents_install">
			<title>Installing Server and Agents</title>

			<para>
				Oden server should be installed in the system in which the deployed file exists.
			</para>

			<para>
				If you extract Oden, you will see the below structure.
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<title>Oden Folder Structure</title>
						<imagedata fileref="../image/Install/file_struct.png" align="center"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		    <para>
		    	In compressed file, there is Oden and Oden Admin. 
		    	Oden can run in Server mode (bin/startup.sh or bin/startup.cmd) 
		    	and in Agent mode (bin/startup-agent.sh or bin/startup-agent.cmd). 
		    	If you want to install only Agent, copy only Oden folder and boot in Agent mode.
		    </para>
		    
		    <para>
				Oden Admin should be installed in a system such as Oden Server. 
				it can be executed right away as bin/startup.sh(bin/startup.cmd), and used in WAS application format.
		    </para>
		    
			<para>
				When run as Oden Agent, refer to conf/agent.ini instead of conf/oden.ini.
		    </para>
		</section>

		<section
			id="install_installinganyframeoden_serverandAgents_configuring">
			<title>Configuring Server and Agents</title>

			<para>
				Oden Server setting can be changed through conf/oden.ini. 
				To apply changes, you should rerun Oden. 
				(In case of Agent, options are supported through conf/agent.ini.)
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							bundle.libs: Oden library list. Among the jar files in bundle folder, 
							only files that are not in this list are active, 
							and the files set in the list are inactive and used only as library. 
							Generally, the user does not need to modify.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							cmd.available: List of commands that can be used. Modify is unnecessary. 
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							log.level: Log level to be logging in log file (1 = error, 2 = warning, 3 =
							info, 4 = debug). Log file can be checked in meta folder. 
							When Oden has a problem, it is used for debugging, and does not generally have to be modified.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							http.port: Port used when communicating with Oden.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.undo: undo 기능 사용 여부. deploy.tmpfile도 true로 설정되어야함.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.tmpfile: 배포 시 임시파일을 사용할 지 여부. true로 설정되면 배포 시 임시파일을 만들어 전송한 뒤, 기존파일을 대체함. 속도가 느림.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.undo.loc: 배포전 기존 파일 백업 위치.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.backupcnt: 배포전 기존 파일 백업 디렉토리 최대 개수.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.exception.option: 배포 오류 발생 시 원복 여부. true로 설정되면 배포 오류 발생 시 배포 작업이 취소. false로 설정되면 오류 파일은 제외하고 나머지 파일 배포작업 수행.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							console.user: 커맨드라인으로 명령어 실행 시 사용할 user id. conf/accounts.txt에 미리 등록되어 있어야 함.  
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deploy.readtimeout: Server에서 Agent로 요청시 응답이 오기까지 대기하는 시간. 기본 120초. deploy.undo가 활성화되어 있을 경우, 백업으로 인해 응답이 오기까지 시간이 오래 걸릴 수 있다. 
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							page.scale, page.cache.size: page처리 시 사용될 기본값. 수정할 필요없음.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							exec.timeout: Time of waiting for command execution.(In ms.) 
							When it is not set, do not end command forcefully, but wait for it to end on its own. 
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							log.duration: Saving time of deployment records. In days. Default is 365.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section
			id="install_installinganyframeoden_serverandAgents_startingup">
			<title>Starting Up Server and Agents</title>

			<para>
				If you have installed and set Oden Server or Agent, 
				you can run Oden as Server mode with the below command. 
			</para>

			<programlisting><![CDATA[bin/startup.sh
(In Windows, move to bin folder of Oden core and execute startup.cmd.)]]></programlisting>

			<para>
				Oden can run in Agent mode with the below command.
			</para>

			<programlisting><![CDATA[bin/startup-agent.sh
(In Windows, move to bin folder of Oden core and execute startup-agent.cmd.)]]></programlisting>

			<para>
				Oden command can be executed through command line after executing Oden Server.  
			</para>
			
			<programlisting><![CDATA[>cd bin
	>runc.sh help
	(In Windows, runc.cmd help)]]></programlisting>
	
			<important>
				<title>Important</title>
				<para>
					When executing Server and Agent, 
					be careful of the ownership and permission of the Target Server file and directory. 
					File deployed through Oden has the ownership and authority (umask) of the user that runs Agent. 
					If the user that runs Agent in the folder to be deployed does not have access, deployment will fail.
				</para>
				<para>
					There should be no blank spaces in the path that Oden is installed. 
					There are blank spaces in Desktop or My Folders in Windows, 
					so Oden will not run properly. 
				</para>
			</important>
		</section>	
		
		<section
			id="install_installinganyframeoden_serverandAgents_managing_accounts">
			<title>Managing Accounts</title>

			<para>
				You can add account with acc.sh(acc.cmd) command of bin folder.  
				For the basically provided account, ID is oden and PWD is oden0. 
			</para>
			
			<programlisting><![CDATA[acc.sh <id> <pwd>
(In Windows, acc.cmd <id> <pwd>)]]></programlisting>
			
			<para>
				You can check the additional accounts in accounts.txt of conf folder. 
				Codes are encoded. The account is deleted when the related line is deleted.
			</para>
			
			<para>
				Define which account to used when deploying in command. 
				It should be defined in console.user field of oden.ini in conf folder. 
				Default is oden. When deleting oden account, change the console.user value to another account. 
			</para>
			
			<note>
				<para>
					In Oden Admin, there is a separate account management function. 
					In this chapter, account management is for web console.
				</para>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section id="install_installinganyframeoden_odenadmin">
		<title>Oden Admin</title>
		
		<section id="install_installinganyframeoden_odenadmin_install">
			<title>Installing Oden Admin</title>
		
			<para>
				You can use Oden Admin independently without a special WAS, 
				and you can use Oden Admin as an application of new WAS. 
			</para>
		
			<section id="install_installinganyframeoden_odenadmin_install_innerwas">
				<title>Use Without a Special WAS</title>
				<programlisting><![CDATA[startup.sh
(In Windows, startup.cmd)]]></programlisting>
				<para>
					Oden Admin start when startup.sh or startup.cmd of admin folder is executed.
				</para>
				<programlisting><![CDATA[http://localhost:9880]]></programlisting>
				<para>
					Admin can be accessed with the above address. Default port is 9880. 
					If you want to change port, open script file (startup.sh or startup.cmd) and change the --httpPort value into the preferred port value. 
				</para>
			</section>
		
			<section id="install_installinganyframeoden_odenadmin_install_outerwas">
				<title>Install in Special WAS</title>
				<para>
					(Tomcat 6.0 onwards copies anyframe.oden.admin.war to webapps folder of WAS. 
					When booting Tomcat, you can access Oden Admin with the below address.)
				</para>
				<programlisting><![CDATA[http://localhost:8080/anyframe.oden.admin]]></programlisting>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>

</section>
