<section id="overview_introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>
		The recent trend for general middle and large-size project processes 
		is to start with defining requirements and moving on to analysis and architecture definition, 
		design, development, execution, etc. 
		Many vendors provide various tools that are specifically for each of these processes. 
		However, unlike the various tools that can be used in the analysis/architecture definition/design stage, 
		there is a shortage in the range of tools that can be used after the development stage. 
		Especially, there are not many options for professional deploy management tools that can deploy 
		development application components to development servers, test servers, or operation servers, etc.
		</para>

	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<title>Something is Missing</title>
			<imagedata fileref="../image/Overview/overview_somethingmissing.png"
				align="left" width="6in"/>
		</imageobject>
	</mediaobject>

	<para>
		Because of the lack of professional deploy management tools, a few problems occurs at the site project.
		</para>
	<para>
		First, deploy management is not automated or standardized, 
		so additional resources are needed when carrying out or operating project.
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Previously, deployment was done through a manual process or by copying with CI engine. 
					To manage this, QAO
					<footnote>
						<para>
							Quality Assurance Officer
						</para>
					</footnote>
					of SA
					<footnote>
						<para>
							Software Architect
						</para>
					</footnote>
					had to carry out professional deploy management
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When there are several Target Servers, work has to be handled repetitively which is complicated.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
<para></para>
	<para>
		Second, it is hard to respond to each deployment method considered during deployment. 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					If there is no professional deploy management tool, 
					it is hard to respond to each of the various deployment methods required at site 
					that include entire deployment, selective deployment, and deployment for only changed items. 
					</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Especially, even though only changed items need to be deployed in development server, 
					many times entire deployment is done because it takes long to compare each item.
					</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When comparing each item, errors occurs because of omissions. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
<para></para>
	<para>
		Third, it is hard to carry out the development and execution stage based on a standardized process. 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Because of the absence of a deployment environment that is processed, 
					work gets disorganized and resources are wasted. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					To address this issue, various functions including deployment policy setting, snapshot/rollback, 
					log analysis, scheduling/assignment, workflow application, etc. are needed.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
<para></para>
	<para>
		Oden provides an automatic deploy environment to overcome these problems.
		</para>

</section>
